"Shiloh" Howard Ames III

Full Stack Developer

Contact

- Portfolio Website
- (2) (757) 746-9387
- shilohhowardames@gmail.com
- Newport News, Virginia 23608

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React JS
- APIs
- C++
- Python
- UI Design
- UX Design
- Jira
- Agile
- Graphic Design

Education

Thomas Nelson Community College, Virginia

August 2021 - Present

Associate of Science in Computer Science

Vice President's List, G.P.A: 4.0

About Me

I am a full stack developer with a solid foundation in both frontend and backend development. I have experience working in a billion dollar, international corporation and with small, local businesses to translate business needs into high-performing, modern websites.

Experience

Front End Developer

February 2022 - June 2022 / North American Plastics, TX

- Redesigned and developed a fully responsive landing page for AIA Plastics with HTML and CSS
- Discussed business needs with executive leadership
- Improved the performance and accessibility of the company website
- · Implemented UX design best practices under leadership of the Design and Development Lead
- Utilized APIs to create dynamic websites

Freelance Front End Developer

April 2022 / Healthy Eatz, VA

- Built a custom website with HTML and CSS
- Consulted with Healthy Eatz, a local vegan restaurant, to create their first ever website
- Implemented accessibility best practices, increased organic traffic

Computer Science Fellow

2021 - Present / Thomas Nelson Community College,VA

- Developed over 40 high-performing programs using Python and C++
- Built a dynamic e-commerce based order management system, ideal for any business to effectively regulate revenue and inventory
- Proposed and designed a program that computes company's yearly inflation rates on products to optimize solutions to business cycle phases and interest rates
- · Learned industry best practices and university-standard coding techniques